

## Hello,

I'm a software engineer who specialises in UI design and UX.

I have over 10 years of industry experience designing and building web applications.

I'm passionate about finding elegant solutions, and adding some flare and magic, to complex problems.

# **Industry Experience**

### SENIOR USER INTERFACE ENGINEER @ CARISTO DIAGNOSTICS

April 2021 → Present

Caristo is an advanced image analysis software company, specialising in detecting the early signs of heart disease from CT scans. This is all done via a web platform which hosts a plethora of tools aimed at professional analysts and clinicians. I work with the product owner to develop prototypes, and the development team to craft these designs into a fully functional user interface. Aside from this, I am solely responsible for the long term development and maintenance of the user interface. This includes researching and selecting the right technologies, and the strategy for implementing them into the product. I have developed our React component library from the ground up. This role has encouraged me to be highly self-lead and independent among a small team. I have really enjoyed the creative freedom that has come with this responsibility.

Tech: React, Docker, Sketch, MobX, Typescript

#### **USER INTERFACE ENGINEER @ EXONAR**

September 2019 → April 2021

Exonar is a data discovery platform that crawls and indexes company data from a multitude of sources. It allows companies to improve governance by providing actionable insights. I worked with the head of UX to develop a powerful web platform capable for visualising and querying huge quantities of structured and unstructured data. I also worked closely with the development team, specialising on the frontend and the UX flow.

Tech: React, Redux, Sketch, Storybook, Jest, D3, GraphQL

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER @ DISCOVER IT

January 2019 → September 2019

Discover IT is a web agency. They design and build web services across a wide array of industries, supporting digital transformation. I worked in a fast paced environment, moving quickly between clients and in-house projects, familiarising myself with new technologies, and frequently switching hats between designer and developer. Success meant producing digital experiences that were responsive, reliable, and visually stunning to wow customers under tight deadlines.

Tech: Vue, React, Sketch, Adobe, CSS, SASS

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ CGI**

September 2012 → December 2018

CGI is a large scale business and IT consultancy. Straight out of school I had exposure to a wide variety of clients and projects that saw me travelling the UK and Europe. I worked for the UK Environment Agency, The Galileo satellite network, the UK Smart Meter program, Shell, the Ministry of Defence and more. For 3 years, I also split my time between university study and full-time employment at CGI under their sponsored degree programme.

Tech: Javascript, D3

# Qualifications

#### BUSINESS MANAGEMENT @ UNIVERSITY OF WINCHESTER

Bachelor's Degree | First Class Honours | 2012 → 2015

Undertook in collaboration with the CGI sponsored degree program. This saw me studying part-time alongside full-time employment at CGI.

### Personal Portfolio

www.dominicbutler.work (out of date)

## Technical Skillset

Storybook Graphic Design Sketch MobX FS<sub>6</sub> Docker css modules React Prototyping Webpack Typescript UI Design Component Design System Vite Jest UX Design D3 Data Visualisation Vue Unit test Node Animation Git Rollup Agile Redux React-router Graph QL NPM